Guide to the Elizabeth Willis DeHuff Collection of American Indian Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Elizabeth Willis DeHuff Collection of American Indian Art
1917-1945
WA MSS S-150
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.6
(15 boxes)
A collection of 199 drawings and watercolors by Pueblo, Navajo, Apache, Cheyenne, and Kiowa artists, much of it student work, collected by Elizabeth Willis DeHuff, wife of a superintendent of the Santa Fe Indian School and an early art instructor of many of the artists.
DeHuff, Elizabeth Willis, 1886-1983
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Elizabeth Willis DeHuff in 1954.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Elizabeth Willis DeHuff (1892-1983)
Elizabeth Willis DeHuff was born to John Turner and Ann Boyd Wilson Willis of Augusta, Georgia in the latter part of the 19th century. Some sources indicate her birth year as 1892, while others suggest it was 1886. She grew up in Augusta, one of five Willis children.
Elizabeth was educated at the Lucy Cobb Institute in Athens, Georgia, and then attended Barnard College in New York City. In 1910, she took a teaching job in the Philippine Islands. While in the Philippines, she met John David DeHuff (1872-1945), another American teacher. Elizabeth returned to the United States, married John David, and in 1913 moved to Carlisle, Pennsylvania where John David assumed a post at the Carlisle Indian School. In 1916, John David was appointed superintendent of the Indian School in Santa Fe, New Mexico and the couple relocated.
Elizabeth became interested in the art and culture of the Southwest. With approval from her husband, she brought boys from the Santa Fe Indian School into the DeHuff home in the afternoons for painting lessons. The boys who received training included Fred Kabotie, Otis Polelonema (both Hopi) and Velino Shije Herrera (of Zia Pueblo). In 1919, she organized an exhibit of her students' art at the Museum of New Mexico.
Controversy erupted around Elizabeth's art instruction when critics of her work with students alleged that the sessions encouraged paganism, emphasizing traditional stories and documenting tribal religious customs. In 1927 John David became secretary of the Santa Fe Chamber of Commerce, a position he held until his death in 1945; the couple left the Santa Fe Indian School and Elizabeth's lessons ceased.
Elizabeth wrote and published several children's stories on Native American themes during and after her experience with Indian School students. Her books include Taytay's Tales, a collection of Indian traditional stories illustrated with the art of her students Fred Kabotie and Otis Polelonema, published in 1922; Taytay's Memories, published in 1924; and Swift Eagle of the Rio Grande, published in 1928. Elizabeth also wrote numerous periodical articles on American Indian, Latin American, and New Mexico historical and cultural topics. She published regularly in the magazine of the Museum of New Mexico, El Palacio. A visible figure in Santa Fe, Elizabeth lectured several nights a week from 1926 through the mid-1940s at the La Fonda Hotel as part of the Santa Fe Railroad's Indian Detours.
The DeHuffs had three children: David, Ann, and Frances. After John David's death in 1945, Elizabeth returned to Georgia where she wrote and undertook genealogical research until her death in 1983.
Scope and Contents
The Elizabeth Willis DeHuff Collection of American Indian Art consists of 199 drawings, paintings, and sketches by Pueblo, Navajo (Diné), Apache, Cheyenne, and Kiowa Indian artists, including many works by young people. The artworks, which date from approximately 1917 to 1945, appear to have been produced primarily between the1920s and the 1940s. The collection reveals the connections and relationships that the DeHuffs cultivated with Indian artists in the Southwest and highlights, in some cases, the development and evolution of the individual style of specific artists and the prominence of certain themes and subjects in their work. The collection reflects Elizabeth DeHuff's interest in the art and culture of the Southwest, and her ongoing support of the artistic expression of young Indians.
The artworks in the collection were created both by DeHuff's students at the Santa Fe Indian School and by other Native artists. In many cases, the age and tribal affiliation of the artists is noted in a caption on the verso or recto of the piece. The drawings and paintings depict traditional stories and figures, traditional social and ceremonial dances, traditional designs, and daily Indian life. A number of the pieces are annotated in pencil, with markings and notes indicating cropping and comments related to printing.
Elizabeth's husband, John David, was the intended recipient of at least ten of the pieces. These artworks bear provenance statements on their verso and appear to have been given to the superintendent in 1917 by John Keirn, a teacher at the Moencopi (Hopi) Day School. The ten works were part of a series of drawings by Grade II and Grade III pupils. Only the first name of the artist was recorded.
An appendix, which indexes the artworks by artist name, has been created to aid researchers using the collection. In both the box and folder listing and the appendix, artists with a traditional Indian name and a name in the European tradition have been listed under the name they preferred to use. When known but not preferred, traditional names have been listed in parentheses after an entry.
Over 55 individual artists are represented in the collection, including Gilbert Benjamin Atencio ( Wah Peen / " Mountain of the Sacred Wind "), Po-Povi Da / " Water Flower ", Velino Shije Herrera ( Ma Pe We / " Oriole " or " Red Bird "), Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ), Julián Martínez ( Pocano or Pho-Ca-No ), Pop Chalee / " Blue Flower ", Santana Roybal Martinez, Tonita Peña ( Quah Ah / " White Coral Beads "), and Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / " Water Edge ").
Arrangement
This collection consists of one main series: Artworks. Items have been boxed according to the size, then alphabetically arranged by artist name.
Index: Artwork by Artist Name
American Indian Painters: A Biographical Directory
Domingo Abeyta. "Indian dance." Box 8, Folder 89
Domingo Abeyta. [Four types of Pueblo dance and drummers]. Box 8, Folder 90
Domingo Abeyta. [Observed Buffalo Dance] and [Three Indian hunters]. Box 8, Folder 91
Annahoho. "This figure comes with the whippers." Box 8, Folder 92
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Male and female San Ildefonso Basket Dancers]. Box 1, Folder 1
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Walking man, sketch for drawing on right] and [Pueblo Man and Woman with basket on her head watching] Box 1, Folder 2
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Pueblo grandmother carrying grandson]. Box 1, Folder 3
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Pueblo Katchina on a blanket]. Box 1, Folder 4
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Skunk and corn basket]. Box 1, Folder 5
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Female Pueblo Rainbow Dancer]. Box 1, Folder 6
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Pueblo clown with basket of fruit]. Box 1, Folder 7
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Female Pueblo clown in yellow manta with cane]. Box 1, Folder 8
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo "Indian Wedding." Box 2, Folder 9
* Gilbert Benjamin Atencio (Wah Peen / "Mountain of the Sacred Wind" ).San Ildefonso Pueblo [Women putting on buckskin leggings]. Box 8, Folder 93
* Pat Atencio ( Koo Peen / "Mountain Rock" ). San Ildefonso Pueblo [Home scene of Pueblo woman and child making pottery]. Box 2, Folder 10
* Awa Tsireh / Cattail Bird. San Ildefonso Pueblo [Owl attacking skunk]. Box 2, Folder 11
* Timothy Begay. Navajo [Figure holding stretched animal]. Box 2, Folder 12
* Allan Bushyhead ( Nakowhoadoniulzi / "Bear Feathers" ). Cheyenne-Arapaho [Cheyenne male dancer]. Box 2, Folder 13
Gonzalio Calabaza. Santo Domingo Pueblo "Shalako figures are about 10 ft. or 12 ft. tall and are carried and manipulated. Their beaks can snap open and shut." Box 15, Folder 181
Gonzalio Calabaza. Santo Domingo Pueblo "Warriors dancing the War Dance." Box 15, Folder 182
Santiago Calabaza. [Three Indian figures]. Box 8, Folder 94
Simon Cata. San Juan Pueblo [Skunk with ear of green corn]. Box 2, Folder 14
Simon Cata. San Juan Pueblo [Turquoise Pueblo man bending over rug with a rope]. Box 2, Folder 15
* Santiago Crispin. [Three types of Pueblo dance and drummers]. Box 8, Folder 95
* Wilson Dewey ( "Sundust" ). San Carlos Apache [Masked figure dancing near fire]. Box 3, Folder 16
* Wilson Dewey ( "Sundust" ). San Carlos Apache [Apache Devil Dancer]. Box 3, Folder 17
* Wilson Dewey ( "Sundust" ). San Carlos Apache [Apache grey spotted dancer]. Box 3, Folder 18
* Earnest [?]. Hopi "Hilili." Box 12, Folder 142
* Earnest [?]. Hopi "-J" Box 12, Folder 143
* Earnest [?]. Hopi "Ku." Box 12, Folder 144
* Earnest [?]. Hopi "Hoo." Box 12, Folder 145
* Earnest [?]. Hopi "[Soyohim?]." Box 12, Folder 146
* Earnest [?]. Hopi "[Soyohim?]." Box 12, Folder 147
* Carlos García ( Nana Tsidé ). San Juan Pueblo [Two Pueblo Kachinas]. Box 3, Folder 20
* Peter García. San Juan Pueblo [Man, likely playing a hoop game]. Box 3, Folder 21
* José Leandro Gutiérrez ( Kgoo Ya ). Santa Clara Pueblo [Male Pueblo Clown chasing a chicken]. Box 3, Folder 22
* Joe Hilario Herrera (See Ru / "Blue Bird"). Cochití Pueblo [Male Cochiti Bow and Arrow Dancer]. Box 3, Folder 23
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Three generations of Zia Pueblo women, painted by 15 year old boy." Box 9, Folder 96
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Woman waving stick at window of building with on looking small creature]. Box 9, Folder 97
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Man shedding bear skin and coming out of cave]. Box 9, Folder 98
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Nature scene of a bird on branch, a lizard on a rock, and a pot on a fire]. Box 9, Folder 99
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Family scene with table of food]. Box 9, Folder 100
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Old man placing hoop over the head of a shapeshifter]. Box 9, Folder 101
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Crying coyote with three birds]. Box 9, Folder 102
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Scaled giant holding Indian man]. Box 10, Folder 103
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Scaled giant running and being attacked with arrows by two Indian men]. Box 10, Folder 104
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Velino Hererra's illustration for New Mexico Magazine." Box 10, Folder 105
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "The Twins took offerings of corn meal and tobacco to Gopher-man to solicit his aid." Box 10, Folder 106
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "One of the Comanches found Maria beneath the altar and dragged her out by the hair." Box 10, Folder 107
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "The Deer began to trip in the holes that Gopher-man had made along his race course." Box 10, Folder 108
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Children's tales (1)." Box 10, Folder 109
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Children's tales (2)." Box 10, Folder 110
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "The white locust went out to bore his way through the hard ground on a tour of investigation. He found water everywhere." Box 10, Folder 111
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "As the women crossed the river to join the men, the Coyote stole the baby the Water Spirit." Box 10, Folder 112
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "In solemn procession, the Indians took the image of the Christ Child around their corn fields." Box 10, Folder 113
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "First Woman covered the things she had gathered together to create the Navajo and covered them with a blanket of mists." Box 10, Folder 114
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "When First Woman took off the blanket of mist, there were the first Navajos." Box 10, Folder 115
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Navajo tale in creation myth 1." Box 10, Folder 116
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Navajo tale in creation myth 2." Box 10, Folder 117
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Navajo tale in creation myth 3 (story of gambling in moccasin game)." Box 10, Folder 118
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Snake Dance legend 1." Box 11, Folder 119
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo "Snake Dance legend 2." Box 11, Folder 120
* Velino Shije Herrera (Ma Pe We / "Oriole" or "Red Bird"). Zia Pueblo [Two hands destroying, one with lightining and one with a cannon]. Box 15, Folder 183
* Justino Herrera (Stimone / "A Bird"). Cochití Pueblo [Two Pueblo Kachinas picking tree branches outside adobe]. Box 4, Folder 24
* Justino Herrera (Stimone / "A Bird"). Cochití Pueblo [Male Cochiti Basket Dancer]. Box 4, Folder 25
* Justino Herrera (Stimone / "A Bird"). Cochití Pueblo [Pueblo masked woman with pot and tree branch]. Box 4, Folder 26
* Partick Swazo Hinds ( "Grey Squirrel" ). Tesuque Pueblo [Pueblo Deer Dancer]. Box 5, Folder 35
* Partick Swazo Hinds ( "Grey Squirrel" ). Tesuque Pueblo [Galloping black horse]. Box 5, Folder 36
Merina Hopkins. See: Pop Chalee
* Allan C. Houser ( Haozous / "Pulling Roots" ). Chiricahua Apache [Apache Devil Dancer]. Box 4, Folder 27
James [?]. Hopi "Hilili (He'le le)." Box 13, Folder 148
James [?]. Hopi "Skelilii." Box 13, Folder 149
James [?]. Hopi "Hilili." Box 13, Folder 150
James [?]. Hopi "Hu." Box 13, Folder 151
James [?]. Hopi [Kachina raising sticks]. Box 13, Folder 152
James [?]. Hopi "Wa'käsi (cow)." Box 13, Folder 153
Walter Johnson. Laguna Pueblo "Cha-be-yo." Box 4, Folder 28
Fredie Kabotie. Hopi "Tu-ni-li'-ni (Navajo word)." and "Oo-wah-nah-zoozoo (Katchina that crushes stones with his mouth)." Box 11, Folder 121
* George Campbell Keahbone ( Asaute ). Kiowa [Abstract of two skunks eating berries]. Box 5, Folder 38
Kokw'e'le. "This is a man dressed as a girl and dances in the sacred rain during the summer." Box 11, Folder 122
* Alfred L. Luján. Taos Pueblo [Running buffalos]. Box 5, Folder 39
Merina Luján. See: Pop Chalee
Adam Martínez. [Three chickens fighting for corn under a rainbow]. Box 11, Folder 123
Adam Martínez. [Black chicken and brown chicken arguing]. Box 11, Folder 124
Adam Martínez. [Skunk and deer]. Box 11, Folder 125
* Julián Martínez (Pocano or Pho-Ca-No ). San Ildefonso Pueblo [Two male Pueblo Comanche Dancers]. Box 11, Folder 126
* Julián Martínez (Pocano or Pho-Ca-No ). San Ildefonso Pueblo [Two male Pueblo Eagle Dancers]. Box 11, Folder 127
* Julián Martínez (Pocano or Pho-Ca-No ). San Ildefonso Pueblo [Snake attacking skunk]. Box 11, Folder 128
* Julián Martínez (Pocano or Pho-Ca-No ). San Ildefonso Pueblo [Pueblo sun and spirit bird design]. Box 11, Folder 129
* Julián Martínez (Pocano or Pho-Ca-No ). San Ildefonso Pueblo [Clown holding a skunk]. Box 11, Folder 130
* Miguel Martínez. San Ildefonso Pueblo "Ah-van-yohs." Box 15, Folder 184
* Phillip Martínez. San Ildefonso Pueblo [Rabbits and birds]. Box 5, Folder 40
Santana Roybal Martinez. San Ildefonso Pueblo "San Ildefonso pueblo pottery design." Box 4, Folder 29
Santana Roybal Martinez. San Ildefonso Pueblo "San Ildefonso pottery design (1)." Box 12, Folder 132
Santana Roybal Martinez. San Ildefonso Pueblo "San Ildefonso pottery design (2)." Box 12, Folder 133
Santana Roybal Martinez. San Ildefonso Pueblo "Bird (parrot) from a San Ildefonso pottery design." Box 12, Folder 134
Santana Roybal Martinez. San Ildefonso Pueblo [San Ildefonso Pueblo pottery design (3)]. Box 12, Folder 135
* Tony / Antonio Martínez. San Ildefonso Pueblo See: Po-Povi Da.
R. Medina. "Zuni Pueblo Pottery design (1)." Box 12, Folder 136
R. Medina. "Zuni Pueblo Pottery design (2)." Box 12, Folder 137
* Eva Mirabel ( Eah Ha Wa / "Green Corn" ). Taos Pueblo [Male Pueblo dancer]. Box 5, Folder 41
* Eva Mirabel ( Eah Ha Wa / "Green Corn" ). Taos Pueblo [Pueblo man linking bundle of red blue and yellow corn]. Box 5, Folder 42
* Eva Mirabel ( Eah Ha Wa / "Green Corn" ). Taos Pueblo [Pueblo woman carrying basket of blue corn on her head]. Box 5, Folder 43
* Eva Mirabel ( Eah Ha Wa / "Green Corn" ). Taos Pueblo [Pueblo woman shucking blue corn]. Box 5, Folder 44
* Vicente Mirabel ( Chiu Tah / "Dancing Boy" ). Taos Pueblo [Marching Kachina with branch]. Box 5, Folder 45
* Stanley C. Mitchell ( Che Chilly Tsosie / "Slim Curley Hair" ). Navajo [Navajo contemporary social couples dance]. Box 5, Folder 46
* Gerónima Cruz Montoya ( Po Tsunu / "Shell" ). San Juan Pueblo "Butterfly Dancer." Box 5, Folder 47
* Gerónima Cruz Montoya ( Po Tsunu / "Shell" ). San Juan Pueblo "Matachina Dancer." Box 5, Folder 48
Severiano Montoya. San Juan Pueblo [Grey horse]. Box 5, Folder 49
* Juanito Moquino. Zia Pueblo [Forest scene with deer and squirrel]. Box 12, Folder 138
* Adolph Naranjo ( Ogowee / "Road Runner" ). Santa Clara Pueblo [Three dancing and singing Pueblo Clowns]. Box 5, Folder 50
* Wesley Nash. Apache [Apache Crown Dancer]. Box 5, Folder 51
* Wesley Nash. Apache "Devil Dancer." Box 5, Folder 52
* Wesley Nash. Apache [Apache Devil Dancer 1]. Box 6, Folder 53
* Wesley Nash. Apache [Apache Devil Dancer 2]. Box 6, Folder 54
* Ignatious Palmer. Mescalero Apache [Donkey in a marsh]. Box 6, Folder 55
Kenneth Pavenyouma. Hopi [Pinto horse eating plant]. Box 6, Folder 56
Tonita Peña ( Quah Ah / "White Coral Beads" ). San Ildefonso Pueblo "Cochiti Pueblo Mountain Sheep Dance." Box 6, Folder 57
Tonita Peña ( Quah Ah / "White Coral Beads" ). San Ildefonso Pueblo [Pueblo woman dancer with white pot and evergreens]. Box 6, Folder 58
* Po-Povi Da / "Water Flower". San Ildefonso Pueblo [Skunk with growing corn and black pot of corn]. Box 6, Folder 59
* Po-Povi Da / "Water Flower". San Ildefonso Pueblo [Sun over two skunks and corn basket]. Box 6, Folder 60
* Po-Povi Da / "Water Flower". San Ildefonso Pueblo [Two skunks with a yellow flower]. Box 6, Folder 61
* Po-Povi Da / "Water Flower". San Ildefonso Pueblo [Skunk with cactus and red flowers]. Box 6, Folder 62
* Po-Povi Da / "Water Flower". San Ildefonso Pueblo [Rain cloud over skunk squirrel and corn basket]. Box 6, Folder 63
* Po-Povi Da / "Water Flower". San Ildefonso Pueblo [Clown on donkey holding a hen]. Box 12, Folder 139
* Pop Chalee / "Blue Flower". Taos Pueblo [Running horses and foxes]. Box 4, Folder 30
* Pop Chalee / "Blue Flower". Taos Pueblo [Mounted hare hunter]. Box 4, Folder 31
* Pop Chalee / "Blue Flower". Taos Pueblo "Shusshe would never drink water except from his cup." Box 4, Folder 32
* Pop Chalee / "Blue Flower". Taos Pueblo "The pony did not like the smell of bear." Box 4, Folder 33
* Pop Chalee / "Blue Flower". Taos Pueblo [Deer in forest]. Box 12, Folder 140
* Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ). Cochiti Pueblo [Male Pueblo Buffalo Dancer]. Box 6, Folder 64
* Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ). Cochiti Pueblo [Orange and white spotted figure with broken watermelon]. Box 6, Folder 65
* Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ). Cochiti Pueblo [Pueblo drummer/singer]. Box 6, Folder 66
* Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ). Cochiti Pueblo [Rain clouds over skunk]. Box 6, Folder 67
* Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ). Cochiti Pueblo [Two men sitting back to back on a donkey]. Box 6, Folder 68
* Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ). Cochiti Pueblo "Burro with wood." Box 6, Folder 69
* Ben Quintana ( Ha A Tee ). Cochiti Pueblo [Deer eating snow]. Box 6, Folder 70
* Joe A. Quintana. Cochiti Pueblo [Skunk family with growing fern and a frog]. Box 7, Folder 71
* Joe A. Quintana. Cochiti Pueblo [White and grey spotted figure with broken watermelon]. Box 7, Folder 72
Alfonso Roybal. See: Awa Tsireh
* [Henry? Henry Jr.?]Shelton. Hopi [Pueblo Kachina doll, pot and rattle displayed on quilt]. Box 7, Folder 73
* Theodore Suina ( Ku-pe-ru / "Snow" ). Cochiti Pueblo "Buffalo Dancer." Box 5, Folder 37
* Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / "Water Edge" ). Navajo [Eagle and fawn]. Box 7, Folder 74
* Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / "Water Edge" ). Navajo [Leaping deer]. Box 7, Folder 75
* Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / "Water Edge" ). Navajo [Mother and bear cub with fish]. Box 7, Folder 76
* Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / "Water Edge" ). Navajo [Navajo old man riding burro]. Box 7, Folder 77
* Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / "Water Edge" ). Navajo [Three geese flying over marsh]. Box 7, Folder 78
* Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / "Water Edge" ). Navajo [Two skunks with ears of corn]. Box 7, Folder 79
* Quincy Tahoma ( Tahoma / "Water Edge" ). Navajo [Pinto horse]. Box 7, Folder 80
Tewe'kwe. "Sword swallowers." Box 12, Folder 141
Nicholas Toledo. Jemez Pueblo [Prancing grey horse]. Box 7, Folder 81
* Pete Vigil. Teauque Pueblo [Kachina with hunted rabbit]. Box 7, Folder 82
* Ultimio Vigil. Teauque Pueblo See: Utimio Vigil.
* Utimio Vigil. Teauque Pueblo [Deer, butterfly, birds and unknown animal, possibly beaver or bear]. Box 7, Folder 83
Unidentified [Pueblo Kachina dancer with bow and arrow] and [Pueblo Kachina chasing man]. Box 4, Folder 34
Unidentified "Buffalo Dancers" and "Navanjigi-la'n-cah (tearing the shirt) Wah-was's-Katchina (Racer)." Box 7, Folder 84
Unidentified [Sketch of Kachina with smaller figure] and [Sketch of Kachina with stick]. Box 7, Folder 85
Unidentified [Sketch of Kachina carrying child in a basket]. Box 7, Folder 86
Unidentified [Turkey on branch]. Box 7, Folder 87
Unidentified [Clown dancing with stick and bird feathers]. Box 7, Folder 88
Unidentified "Salymobier." Box 13, Folder 154
Unidentified "Kayemshi." Box 13, Folder 155
Unidentified [Green and Black Kachina] and [Kachina running from dark cloud with rattle]. Box 13, Folder 156
Unidentified "Ah-nate Katchina (Long Hair)" and "Bird maiden." Box 13, Folder 157
Unidentified "Ko-Ko-purl-mana / Insect fly - dragonfly" and "Hoo-lulu (Sound he makes gives name)." Box 13, Folder 158
Unidentified [Kachina carrying bow with evergreens] and "Coo-yen-tsi." Box 13, Folder 159
Unidentified [Four Kachinas chasing a man] and [Kachina with blue embroidered kilt]. Box 13, Folder 160
Unidentified [Woman speaking with Kachina]. Box 13, Folder 161
Unidentified [Two Kachinas, one with green bushel] and [Ball game overseen by figure]. Box 13, Folder 162
Unidentified [Kachina pointing finger] and [Man chasing Kachina and clown teasing man]. Box 13, Folder 163
Unidentified "Sketch of [two red] mudhead figures]. Box 13, Folder 164
Unidentified [Navajo couples dance]. Box 13, Folder 165
Unidentified [Navajo woman feeding dogs]. Box 14, Folder 166
Unidentified [Navajo man picking plants accompanied by black horse]. Box 14, Folder 167
Unidentified [Navajo men and women seated indoors]. Box 14, Folder 168
Unidentified [Navajo men seated indoors with shoes]. Box 14, Folder 169